Fatmir Likrama

Houston, TX +1 512 784 9641 <u>limanoa@gmail.com</u> <u>https://flikrama.github.io/</u>

Engineering professional with consulting, project management, statistics, data analysis and machine learning experience. Published in signal processing and data science. Strong analytical skills with a background in Physics and Engineering with proven communication skills.

Skills

- Proficient user of Python and SQL, familiar with C++/C# and Visual Basic
- Experience with AWS and Azure cloud environments
- Multiple project experience using Scikit-Learn, Tensor Flow as well as several web scraping and signal processing Python packages
- Trained in Apache Spark
- Proficient with Power BI and SPSS, familiar with Tableau

Data Science Project Experience

- Lead Neural Network, Clustering and Fuzzy Logic algorithm implementation for rock typing and classification in commercial Petrophysics products
- Pioneered machine learning workflow to Geomechanical modeling of natural gas stimulation success—expandable to other applications
- Researched and published on time series analysis and signal processing (wavelet transform) and automatic change point detection methodology
- Developed scripts for seamless data transfer from geological to FEM platforms

Employment Experience

Rock Physics Product Owner, Landmark Software, Halliburton

6/2019 - 5/2020

Houston, TX

- Managed a multimillion revenue generating products portfolio within an Agile framework
- Developed roadmap and vision for Rock Physics products and maintained relationships with client
- Accomplished product migration to cloud within 6 months

Consultant/Project Manager, 5/2012 - 6/2019 Houston, TX Halliburton

- Brought on average more than \$500k yearly revenue to the organization by performing Geomechanics Consulting/Project Management work for operators all around the globe and much more by pull-through
- Enhanced organization offerings' portfolio by addition of workflow for 4D Geomechanical modeling and wellbore stability considering shale swelling chemical effects

Self Employed Tutor, Self Employed

1/2009 - 5/2012

Austin, TX

Tutored undergraduate and graduate students in person and online on Statistics, various Math classes, Physics and Chemistry

Engineering Intern, Schlumberger

5/2007 - 8/2007

Sugar Land, TX

Modeled mud filtrate invasion, fluid flow to a sampling probe and drilling mud filtrate clean up in a Wireline Formation Testing utilizing Eclipse 300 Reservoir modelling software

Research Assistant, University of Texas at Austin

6/2006-12/2008

Austin, TX

Collaborated in research led by Dr Jon Olson and Prof Mukul Sharma on coupled fluid dynamics and mechanics of weakly cemented and un-cemented formations, permeability variation, stress and fracture reorientation and wellbore failure analysis modeling

Education

University of Texas at Austin, Master of Science in Engineering, PE

8/2006 - 12/2008

Austin, TX

Thesis: Study of Mechanical and Flow Properties of Weakly Cemented and Un-cemented Sands Using Discrete Element Method Modeling

Bogazici University, Bachelor of Science, Physics

9/1999 - 6/2003

Istanbul, Turkey

Graduated ranking top of 2003 class, Physics Department

Publications

- SPE-195889-MS, 2019: Improved Understanding of Dynamic Fracture Behavior in Unconventional Horizontal Wells Using Wavelet Transformation
- ARMA 2019-431: Inferring Current Day and Paleo Stress Orientation from Natural Fracture Geometry
- AAPG 2017: Conducting Integrated Reservoir Studies in Quartzite Hamra-Reservoir-Tight Oil, Southern Periphery of Hassi Messaoud Field, Algeria
- ARMA 2016-514: Workflow on Incorporating Thick-Walled Cylinder Test Results in Finite Element Models of near Wellbore for Sanding Prediction Studies
- ARMA 2015-212: A Practical Log-Based Approach on Assessing and Preventing Wellbore Instability Considering Both Mechanical and Shale Swelling Effects

US Citizen since 2015